Oz Nahum Tiram, M.Sc.

Hochstr. 40

90429 Nürnberg Mobile: +49 176 82098294

E-mail: oz.tiram@gmail.com *WWW:* oz123.github.io

Solving interesting problems, isn't only about finding the best algorithm, or choosing the right data structure or tool. Software is made for computers, but it needs to be understood by people, not only developers. My experience through the years has thought me that no buzz-word or new fancy technology can replace good team work. Good software projects are made with good tools and practices. Great software projects are made by great teams.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Consultant Self-Employed

March 2020 - Current

- Design and build Kubernetes clusters on Bare Metal, AWS and Oracle Cloud.
- Kubernetes and Cloud Native Consulting and Training.
- Build web applications using Python and Go.
- · Co-Organizer official Kubernetes and official CNCF meetup for the region



Senior IT Architect noris network ag

March 2018 - March 2020

- In-house and customer facing consultant for cloud native technologies.
- Plan and Deploy Kubernetes\Openshift clusters on OpenStack\vSphere
- · Lead distributed development teams
- Lead developer of in house Kubernetes distribution
- · Certified Kubernetes Administrator



Lead Developer The Mobility House GmbH

August 2016 - February 2018

- Write Jenkins CI\CD pipelines
- · Plan and Deploy Kubernetes clusters on AWS
- · Build Infrastructure with SaltStack, Docker, AWS
- Develop Micro-Services using Python, Go and RabbitMQ
- Interview and hire developers
- Mentor Junior Developers



Lead DevOps + Data Engineer Plan-Net GmbH

August 2014 - August 2016

- · Lead migration from Subversion to Git
- Develop ETL jobs in python python-pandas and multiple other python libraries.
- Develop extraction jobs from MongoDB to tableau using C and Python APIs.
- Maintain a cluster of multiple MongoDB replication and shard nodes.
- Inrastructure planning and rolling with salt-stack.
- Build Web UIs for reporting using python-flask and JavaScript.



See older positions at the end.

EDUCATION

M. Sc. Applied Env. Geosciences Universität Tübingen, Germany

October 2008 - October 2010

Thesis Title:

Implementation of Sequential Non Iterative approach in MIN3P reactive transport code and comparison of Global Implicit Method, final GPA 1.6.

B.Sc. Geology Hebrew University, Jerusalem

October, 2003 - March, 2008

B.Sc. Final GPA 88/100.

RECENT OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS & CONTRIBUTIONS

I contribute to numerous open source projects in various forms. Recent examples are:

- Kubernetes documentation, official Python client, Support of OpenRC and more.
- CoreDNS plugin for getting DNS records from NetBox
- Maintain Gentoo ebuilds
- Janet SQLITE binding
- Submitting patches to Python's STL, SaltStack
- Report and triage bugs in multiple applications I use

The list is too long to include all here. Check my Github profile for more software project I work on.

PUBLIC SPEAKING AND WORKSHOPS

- CICD with K8S and Gitlab, DevOps Conference, Berlin, 2021.
- Keynote 30 Years of Python, Python Summit, Berlin, 2021.
- Designing and Building K8S clusters with kubeadm, DevOps Conference, London, 2020.
- Keynote Going cloud German Openstack days, Berlin, 2019.
- Advanced Flow Control in Python, Python Summit, Berlin, 2018, again in 2019.
- Secure Continuous Delivery in Kubernets Clusters, DevOps Days, Berlin, 2018.
- Building a WSGI framework, PloneConf, Barcelona, 2017.
- Advanced Python workshop, PloneConf, Boston, 2016.
- Co-Organizer CNCF Meetup Nürnberg.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother language: Hebrew.

Other languages*:	Understanding		Speaking	Writing
	Listening	Reading		
English	C2	C2	C2	C2
German	C2	C2	C2	C2
* Evaluation according to Common European Framework of Reference (CEF).				

DRIVING LICENSE

PKW, Private Auto, Class B.

WORK PERMIT

German Citizen

Eligible to work and live in EU\Canada.

SKILLS MATRIX

Level of skill:

- 6. I could write a book about it.
- 5. Used in multiple projects, contributed bug reports, submitted patches.
- 4. Have done more than 3 projects, involving more than 8000 line of code.
- 3. Used in production, worked on a few small scale projects.
- 2. Have done single small scale project, used it occasionally.
- 1. Took a course in the university, read a single book.

Scripting\Dynamic Languages

Language	Skill Level
Python	6
BASH	4
JavaScript	4
Groovy	3

Compiled Languages

Go	5
JAVA	3
С	3
C++	2
Fortran	2
Pascal	1

Markup & Web

LATEX	5
Sphinx\reStructuredText	5
HTML	3
CSS	2

Operating Systems

Gentoo	5
Red Hat\CentOS	5
Debian	5
SuSE	4
Windows	3
FreeBSD	2
OS X	2

Python Frameworks & Development tools

Flask\Bottle	5
pytest	5
Django	4
Splinter\Selenium	4
Git	5
Make	4

Databases

MongoDB	4
SQLite	4
MySQL	3
PostgreSQL	3
Oracle	1

DevOps tools & Clouds

Kubernetes	5
SaltStack	5
Ansible	4
Jenkins	4
AWS	4
OpenStack	4
Docker	4
Packer	4
Vagrant	4
Gitlab CI\CD	4
Docker-compose	3
Terraform	3

OLDER POSITIONS AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer Agnitas AG

May 2014 - August 2014

Backend development of a high traffic E-Mail marketing SaaS.

- Develop internal tools using flask and sqlalchemy automate work flows.
- Extend continuous integration and introduce automated Selenium driven testing.
- Standardization of code packages, setuptools, coverage.py, code analysis & review.
- Manage work flows with Jira.
- Write sphinx documentation for python libraries developed in-house



Software Engineer, System Engineer Science+Computing AG

January 2011 - January 2014

My tasks as Software Engineer were:

- Develop different custom software solution for internal customers and external customers.
- Develop eclipse plug-ins that are part of OpenMDM project.
- Develop a Django front end for managing multiple user accounts in LDAP and Active Directory.
- Implement back-end scripts to synchronize AD user accounts and LDAP accounts.
- Setup and configure OpenLDAP.
- Work on multiple Django projects.
- Contribute to PDMCAE (Data management software in BMW written in C, C++, Perl, Pl\SQL)



My tasks as System Engineer were:

- Install and Configure Windows and Linux (Red Hat 5,6 and CentOS) Workstations.
- Install and Configure HPC Clusters.
- Scripting: BASH, Python and Perl.
- Backup tool: TSM Client\Server support (On Windows and Linux).
- Hardware and Software RAID configuration.
- Monitoring (Nagios\RRDtool) Queuing systems (Sun Grid Engine\In house queuing system).
- Windows\Linux sharing (CIFS & SAMBA).
- 2nd level support for Engineers using CAE\CAD software.
- Install and configure MySQL databases.
- Install and configure SAN such as AutoFS, AMD and Windows DFS.
- Maintain LDAP servers.
- Actively responsible for packaging software in RPM, DEB and other packaging format.
- Responsible for as much as 5000 computers (Workstations and cluster nodes) for renowned customers such Daimler, Porsche and BMW.



Scientific Programmer Uni. British Columbia, Vancouver.

May, 2010 - Oct., 2010

- Implement a sequential version of a reactive transport model (Ground water flow + Chemical reactions) using an existing large and complex Fortran code.
- Write a collection of Python scripts: to submit jobs on different cluster hosts with different input files, to process the results and visualize them.
- The results of the code work and benchmarking comparing to previous versions were submitted as M.Sc thesis.



System Administrator, Python Programmer Uni. Tübingen, Germany

- Install and configure home brewed 2 Debian clusters with 20 compute nodes.
- Setup Subversion & Trac servers.
- Implement Python application to process GIS data and visualize the results (see blow MMSPy).
- Maintain firewalls to the Clusters and the TRAC server.

 Debian
 Trac
 Subversion
 Python
 GDAL
 GIS
 IPTables
 PfSense

System Administrator Rankabove, Israel

April, 2008 - August, 2008

Oct. 2008 - April 2010

- Configuration management of Windows, OSX desktops and Ubuntu\Debian Servers.
- Install and maintain Bugzilla for our clients.
- Package software (DEB format) for deployment.

Debian Packaging Bugzilla Ubuntu Shell Python OSX Windows